Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Asia Serials TAM.779
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Asia Serials
1940-2008
1970-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.779
8.9 Linear Feet in 14 manuscript boxes and 11 flat boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Asia Serials contains over 100 titles published in and about East Asia and Southeast Asia between 1940 and 2008. The bulk of the collection dates from the 1970s and the 1980s. Topics include political and social issues throughout Asia, arts in Asia, and Asian American communities and organizations in the United States.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to Asia drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Asia Serials contains over 100 titles published in and about East Asia and Southeast Asia between 1940 and 2008. The bulk of the collection dates from the 1970s and the 1980s and consists of serials published in Hong Kong, China, New York, and California in the 1970s and the 1980s. Topics include political and social issues in China, Japan, North Korea, South Korea, Hong Kong, and Taiwan, as well as diplomatic and political relations between these countries and the United States (US). Other topics include Asian and Asian American arts and literature; racial equality for Asian Americans in the US, particularly in California and New York; and cultural and political activities in Hong Kong, California, and New York. The collection contains a number of newspapers published for Chinese American, Indian, and Filipino communities San Francisco, New York City, and other cities in the US, and by Asian American organizations concerned with human rights issues in China and North Korea. Large runs include East West from San Francisco, California and Issues & Studies from Taiwan.
Serials (publications); Asian Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Asian Americans -- California -- Periodicals.; Asian Americans -- New York (State) -- New York -- Periodicals.; East Asia -- Foreign Relations -- 20th century.; East Asia -- Periodicals.; Southeast Asia -- Periodicals.
- A. Magazine, The Asian American Quarterly: Metro East Publications, Inc., New York, NY, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Actual Action: Actual Action Editorial Commity, Tokyo, Japan, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- AFNY News Forum: Asians & Friends--New York, Inc., New York, NY, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ang Katipunan: Union of Democratic Filipinos, Oakland, CA, 1977-1986 (Box 14, Folder 2-10)
- Artspiral: Asian American Arts Centre, New York, NY, 1988-1993 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
- Asia in Washington: Asia Society. Washington Center, Washington, DC, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Asian American Resource Workshop Newsletter: Asian American Resource Workshop, Boston, MA, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Asian Americans for Equality: Asian Americans for Equality, Inc., New York, NY, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Asian New Yorker: Asian New Yorker Company, New York, NY, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Asian-America Spirit: East Coast Asian Student Union, Boston, MA, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Asians & Friends New York: Asians & Friends--New York, Inc., New York, NY, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bridge: Southeast Asia Resource Action Center, Washington, DC, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CAAV (Committee Against Anti-Asian Violence) Voice: Committee Against Anti-Asian Violence, New York, NY, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- CCAS Newsletter: CCAS, Stanford, CA, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Cheng Ming: Pak Ka Publisher, Hong Kong, 1979 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 13)
- China & World Cultural Exchange: Cultural Exchange, Beijing, China, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- China At Work: Society for Anglo-Chinese Understanding, London, UK, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
- China Daily News: China Daily News, New York, NY, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- China Digest: China Digest Association, Hong Kong, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- China Friendship: US-China Peoples Friendship Association, Cleveland, OH, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- China News Digest: United Service to China, New York, NY, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- China Policy Study Group Broadsheet: China Policy Study Group, London, UK, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- China Update: Yale-China Association, New Haven, CT, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Chinese American Forum: Chinese American Forum, Inc., Silver Springs, MD, 1986-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2-9)
- Chinese People's Institute of Foreign Affairs Journal: Chinese People's Institute of Foreign Affairs, Beijing, China, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- CICC Currents: Chinese Information and Culture Center, New York, NY, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
- City Magazine: The Tabloid Coop, Wanchai, Hong Kong, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 2-6)
- Committee Bridges: Committee of 100, New York, NY, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Contas do Exercicio e da Gerencia de 1944 da Reparticao Tecnica das Obras Publicas: Imprensa Nacional de Macau, Macau, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Kilusang Mayo Uno International Department, Manila, Philippines, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Currents: Chinese Information and Culture Center - Taipei Economic and Cultural Office in New York, New York, NY, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Da Cheng: Da Cheng Za Zhi She, Honk Kong, 1973 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 4)
- Debate: The Philippine Left Review: Debate, Amsterdam, Netherlands, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- DiverseCity: Humanist Center of Cultures, New York, NY, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- E. Timor Update: East Timor Human Rights Committee, Syracuse, NY, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- East West: East/West Chinese-American Journal, Inc., San Francisco, CA, 1985-1990 (Box 15, Folder 7-9, Box 16, Folder 1-8, Box 17, Folder 1-7, Box 18, Box 19)
- East West: East/West Publishing Co., San Francisco, CA, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Eastern Horizon: Eastern Horizon Press, Hong Kong, China, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
- Echoes From Tiananmen: Friends of Chinese Minzhu, Kowloon, Hong Kong, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
- Eurasiam Bilingual Monthly Magazine: Eurasiam Magazine Co., Inc., New York, NY, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Handbook of Japanese Financial/Industrial Combines, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Image: Organization of Chinese Americans, Inc., Washington, DC, 1979-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8, Box 20, Folder 2)
- Indian-American: SRIR Communications, Inc., New York, NY, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Indusco Bulletin: Indusco, Inc., New York, NY, 1944-1951 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Indusco Inc.: Balie Schools: Indusco, Inc., New York, NY, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Inquiry Magazine: East Timor Research Project, Ithaca, NY, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Issues & Studies: Institute of International Relations, Taipei, Taiwan, 1981-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5-9, Box 6, Folder 1-7, Box 7, Box 8, Folder 1-6, Box 9, Box 10, Folder 1-5)
- Japan Times Weekly: The Japan Times, Tokyo, Japan, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Kalayaan International: Kalayaan International, San Francisco, CA, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 4-8)
- Katipunan: Katipunan Publications, Oakland, CA, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Korea: Committee for Solidarity with the Korean People, San Francisco, CA, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Korea Information Bulletin: Foreign Languages Publishing House, Democratic People's Republic of Korea, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Korea Labour: Korea Research and Information Center, Seoul, South Korea, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Korea Today: Foreign Languages Publishing House, Pyongyang, Democratic People's Republic of Korea, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Korea Update: Korea Coalition, Washington, DC, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Korea: Or the Third World War: Contemporary Press, New York, NY, Undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Korean Affairs: General Association of Korean Residents in Japan, Pyongyang, Democratic People's Republic of Korea, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Kuguk Chonson: The National Salvation Front: The Mission of the National Democratic Front of South Korean in Japan, Tokyo, Japan, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Letters from China: Letters from China, Peking, China, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Lettre de Chine: Lettre de Chine, Peking, China, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Libero International: Libero International Editorial Collective, Osaka, Japan, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Movement: Asian Students Association, Kowloon, Hong Kong, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Nan Bei Ji: Long Men Wen Hua Shi Ye You Xian Gong Si, Juilong, China, 1971 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 8)
- New Asian Standard: The New Asian Standard, New York, NY, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- New Asian Times: The New Asian Times Co., Inc., New York, NY, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- New Dawn: J-Town Collective, San Francisco, CA, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 10, Box 21, Folder 5)
- New Hopes and New Challenges of the 90s: Asian Americans For Equality, New York, NY, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- New India Bulletin: Indian People's Association in North America, Montreal, Quebec, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- New Korea: Librairie "Min Chu", Canton, China, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- New York Nichibei: Japanese American News Corp., New York, NY, 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- News - OCA New York Chapter: Organization of Chinese Americans, Inc., New York, NY, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- News China: China Newsweek Corporation, Beijing, China, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- News from Asia Watch: Asia Watch, Washington, DC, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- News From Japanese Press: PTTI Tokyo Office, Tokyo, Japan, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- News Letter: Japanese American Committee for Democracy, New York, NY, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Newsletter: Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund (AALDEF, Inc.), Oakland, CA, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Newsletter: Association for Asian American Studies, unkown, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Newsletter: Embassy of the People's Republic of China, Washington, DC, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Newsletter: Movement for a Free Philippines, Briarwood, NY, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Nexus: China BRIDGE Magazine Co., Beijing, China, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
- Ningas: Ningas Corporation, New York, NY, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- October Review: October Review, Kowloon, Hong Kong, 1984-1990 (Box 12, Folder 2, Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 12)
- Orcamento Ordinario da Receita e Despesa: Da Provedoria da Assistencia Publica de Macau para o Ano Economico de 1963: Imprensa Nacional de Macau, Macau (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Outlook: Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund, New York, NY, 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Overseas Times: Overseas Times Corp., Jersey City, NJ, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Pacific Citizen: Japanese American Citizens League, Los Angeles, CA, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Pacific Imperialism Notebook: Pacific Rim Project, San Francisco, CA, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Pacific: Revue des Asiatiques: Pacific, Paris, France, 1954-1956 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- PAG-ASA Newsletter: Philippine American Group-Advocates for Social Action, New York, NY, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- People's War: The People's War, London, UK, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Philippines Mail: Filipino-American Media of California, San Francisco, CA, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Qi Shi Nian Dai = The Seventies: Qi Shi Nian Dai Za Zhi She, Hong Kong, 1977 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 9)
- Quan Cha Jia (The Observers Monthly): Quan Cha Jia Chu Ban She, Hong Kong, circa 1978 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 10)
- Regulamento do Imposto do Selo: Imprensa Nacional de Macau, Macau, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Remodelacao dos Vencimentos dos Funcionarios Civis e Militares da Colonia de Macau: Imprensa Nacional de Macau, Macau, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- RICE: Rice Magazine Enterprises, San Francisco, CA, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Rodan: Northern California Asian American Community, San Francisco, CA, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Rungh: Rungh Cultural Society, Vancouver, BC, Undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
- SAMAR: SAMAR, New York, NY, 1994-2001 (Box 12, Folder 13-14, Box 13, Folder 1)
- Sambayanan Newsletter: Sambayanan, New York, NY, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Sampan: Chinese American Civic Association, Boston, MA, 1987-1995 (Box 22, Folder 1-6, Box 23, Box 24, Folder 1-4)
- Seoro Seoro: Seoro Korean Cultural Network, New York, NY, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- South-North Dialogue in Korea: Public Relations Association of Korea, Seoul, South Korea, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Southwest Chinese Journal: Southwest Chinese Journal, Houston, TX, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Spark: South Asia Students Association, UC-Berkeley, Berkeley, CA, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Sphulinga: Bangladesh Association, Quebec, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Ta Kung Pao: Ta Kung Pao (Hongkong) Co., Hong Kong, China, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Taishu: Taishu, San Francisco, CA, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Taiwan Industrial Relations Bulletin: Chung Hua Institute for Industrial Relations, Taipei, Taiwan, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Thai Bulletin: Union of Democratic Thais, Chicago, IL, Undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Thai Review: American Friends Service Committee, Pasadena, CA, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Thailand Update: Thailand Update, Langley Park, MD, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- The 2nd Generation: New York Asian News, Inc., New York, NY, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- U.S. China Friendship Newsletter: U.S. China Friendship Association, San Francisco, CA, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- U.S.-Korea Review: The U.S.-Korea Foundation, Washington, DC, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- UGAT: Philippine Center for Immigrant Rights, Inc., New York, NY, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Wei Min: Wei Min She, San Francisco, CA, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Wen Hua Xin Chao: Wen Hua Chao She, Hong Kong, 1978 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 6)
- Women of China: Women of China, Beijing, China, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Xiang Ya Ta Wai: Wen Ya You Xian Gong Si, Hong Kong, circa 1975 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 5)
- Xin Wen Zi Zhou Kan: Shanghai Xin Wen Zi Gong Zuo Zhe Xie Hui, Shanghai, China, 1949-1951 (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 7)
- Yao Bai Wen Yi (Box Shared Tamiment 062, Folder 11)